<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Cognitive Measures</string>

    <string name="agreement">The following are a series of cognitive tasks, several of which are the versions of the tasks you completed in the original Project Talent
        study.\n\n
        \t&#8226; Read the instructions for each task carefully.\n
        \t&#8226; Do the best you can. If you are unsure of the right answer, pick the one you think is the best.\n
        \t&#8226; If a task includes multiple-choice questions, select only one answer.\n
        \t&#8226; There is only one right answer for each question.\n\n
        Press the NEXT button to begin the first task.</string>
    <string name="finish_message">You have completed the puzzles.\n\n
        IMPORTANT! Please press \"Finish\" to be sure all of your answers are saved.\n\n
        Once you press \"Finish\" the program will close. Press the droidSURVEY button to complete the survey questions.</string>

    <string name="begin">Begin</string>
    <string name="button_str_back">Back</string>
    <string name="finishbutton_str">Finish</string>

    <!-- Vocabulary strings -->
    <string name="vo_text">INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
        This task contains words for you to define. The items are multiple choice - select the best response for each word.
    </string>
    <string name="vocabulary">Vocabulary</string>
    <string name="vocab3">
          [
            {
               \"question\": \"A vacuum is a space containing\",
               \"options\": [\"Ozone\",
                        \"Helium\",
                        \"Carbon monoxide\",
                        \"Nitrogen\",
                        \"Nothing\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"To surrender means to\",
                \"options\": [\"Fight\",
                       \"Conquer\",
                        \"Retreat\",
                        \"Surround\",
                        \"Yield\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Obstruction means\",
                \"options\": [\"Obeisance\",
                        \"Obstacle\",
                        \"Obstinacy\",
                        \"Obstreperousness\",
                        \"Obtuseness\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 1
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab1">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"A diagram is a kind of\",
               \"options\": [\"Route\",
                        \"Building\",
                        \"Measurement\",
                        \"Drawing\",
                        \"Grammatical error\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 3
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"To discard is to\",
                \"options\": [\"Gamble\",
                       \"Hide\",
                        \"Lie\",
                        \"Take away\",
                        \"Throw away\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Blunt means\",
                \"options\": [\"Heavy\",
                        \"Dangerous\",
                        \"Weak\",
                        \"Sharp\",
                        \"Dull\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 4
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab2">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"Which of these is not a measuring device?\",
               \"options\": [\"Caliper\",
                        \"Protractor\",
                        \"Voltmeter\",
                        \"Gauge\",
                        \"Solder\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 4
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A purpose of lubrication is to\",
                \"options\": [\"Prevent motion\",
                       \"Increase heat\",
                        \"Reduce friction\",
                        \"Prevent warping\",
                        \"Remove dirt\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 2
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Restricted means\",
                \"options\": [\"Scolded\",
                        \"Redesigned\",
                        \"Limited\",
                        \"Refrained\",
                        \"Tense\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 2
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab4">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"To retain means to\",
               \"options\": [\"Get\",
                        \"Give up\",
                        \"Keep\",
                        \"Lose\",
                        \"Create\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 2
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A municipal court is a\",
                \"options\": [\"City court\",
                       \"State court\",
                        \"Federal court\",
                        \"United Nations court\",
                        \"Military court\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 0
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Which of these is carnivorous?\",
                \"options\": [\"Chipmunk\",
                        \"Cow\",
                        \"Horse\",
                        \"Tiger\",
                        \"Elephant\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 3
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <string name="vocab5">
         [
            {
               \"question\": \"Magnitude means\",
               \"options\": [\"Generosity\",
                        \"Size\",
                        \"Location\",
                        \"Kindness\",
                        \"Direction\"
                        ],
                \"answer\": 1
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"Eccentric means\",
                \"options\": [\"Odd\",
                       \"Feeble-minded\",
                        \"Stingy\",
                        \"Temperamental\",
                        \"Solitary\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 0
            },
            {
                \"question\": \"A barometer is used to measure\",
                \"options\": [\"Temperature\",
                        \"Rainfall\",
                        \"Humidity\",
                        \"Air pressure\",
                        \"Cloudiness\"
                       ],
                \"answer\": 3
            }
          ]
    </string>
    <!-- Vocabulary strings -->

    <!-- Number Series -->
    <string name="ns_section_title">Number Series</string>
    <plurals name="ns_instr">
        <item quantity="one">Please enter the number that belongs in the empty box. Then press \'Next\' to continue. </item>
        <item quantity="other">Please enter the number that belongs in the empty boxes. Then press \'Next\' to continue.</item>
    </plurals>
    <string name="title_activity_sec_nsex2_a_">Example 2 Answer</string>
    <string name="ns_intro">
		INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
        &#8226; You will now see six more questions like the ones you just did.\n
		&#8226; Please enter the number that belongs in each empty box.\n
        &#8226; The numbers might increase, like 2, 4, 6, or decrease, like 6, 4, 2.\n
		&#8226; You may be asked a question with more than one empty box in the sequence.\n
		&#8226; Some of the questions may be easy but others may be hard. Just do the best you can.\n\n
		If you are ready to begin, please press \'Next\' to continue.
	</string>
    <string name="clear">Undo</string>
    <string name="clicknext">Please press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="ns_example1">
        {
          \"id\": 1,
          \"question\": \"INSTRUCTIONS\n\n In this task, on each screen you will see several numbers that make up a series. There will be one or more empty boxes
        somewhere in the series. Sometimes an empty box will be at the end of the series, sometimes in the middle, and sometimes at the
        beginning. Please tap the number buttons to enter the number that goes into each empty box. The answer will be a number between 0 and 99.\n\n
        Here is an example. Enter the number that goes in the empty box. Then press \'Next\' to continue.\",
         \"options\": [1, 2, 3, 4],
         \"ansPosition\": 2,
          \"answerText\": \"INSTRUCTIONS\n\nThe answer we were looking for is 3, so the completed sequence is:\"
        }
    </string>
    <string name="ns_example2">
        {
          \"id\": 2,
          \"question\": \"INSTRUCTIONS\n\nBelow is another example.\nPlease enter the number that belongs in the empty box. Then press \'Next\' to continue.\",
          \"options\": [2, 4, 6, 8],
          \"ansPosition\": 3,
          \"answerText\": \"INSTRUCTIONS\n\nThe answer we were looking for is 8 because the numbers (2, 4, 6, 8) increase by 2. The completed sequence is:\"
        }
    </string>
    <string name="ns_3">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [8, 10, 12, 14],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [23, 26, 30, 35, 41],
            \"ansPosition\": 4
          },
          {
            \"options\": [18, 17, 15, 12, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_1">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [6, 7, 8, 9],
            \"ansPosition\": 2
          },
          {
            \"options\": [6, 5, 4, 3],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [5, 8, 11, 14],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_2">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [2, 4, 6, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 0
          },
          {
            \"options\": [1, 3, 3, 5, 7, 7, 9],
            \"ansPosition\": 6
          },
          {
            \"options\": [18, 10, 6, 4, 3],
            \"ansPosition\": 3
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_4">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [17, 15, 12, 8],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [10, 6, 3, 1],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [17, 16, 14, 10, 2],
            \"ansPosition\": 4,
            \"ansOptions\": [2, 3]
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <string name="ns_5">
        [
          {
            \"options\": [17, 20, 26, 38, 62],
            \"ansPosition\": 0
          },
          {
            \"options\": [5, 7, 11, 19, 35],
            \"ansPosition\": 1
          },
          {
            \"options\": [70, 72, 76, 84],
            \"ansPosition\": 1,
            \"ansPositions\": [1, 2],
            \"ansMultiOptions\": [[72, 76], [78, 82]]
          }
        ]
    </string>
    <!-- Number series -->

    <!-- Abstract reasoning -->
    <string name="ar_section_title">Abstract Reasoning</string>
    <string name="ar_text">INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
		Each item in this task consists of a set of figures arranged in a pattern formed according to certain rules. Look at the following patterns in the example.
	</string>
    <string name="ar_text1">The question mark (?) in the lower right corner of the box shows where a figure is missing in the pattern. Choose which of the five
        figures (A, B, C, D or E) under the pattern belongs where the \"?\" is.\n\n
        Then press \"Next\" to continue.</string>

    <string name="ar_text3">In the case of the example, the correct answer is E. In the top row, the figure at the right is the same as the one to the left of it
        except that it has been turned upside down. Following these rules, the figure that goes at the \"?\" should be larger than the one above it, and exactly the same
        size as the one to the left of it, but upside down. Therefore, E is the correct answer.\n\n
        Please press \"Next\" to continue.
	</string>

    <string name="ar_instr1">INSTRUCTIONS\n\nIn each question, you are to decide what figure belongs where the \"?\" is in the pattern. To do this you have
        to figure out what the rule is according to which the drawings change, going from row to row, and what the rule is for the changes going from column to column.
        The items have different kinds of patterns and different rules by which the drawings change.\n\nPlease press \"Next\" to continue.</string>

    <string name="start_task">Would you like to see another example, or are you ready to start this task?</string>
    <string name="example">Another example</string>
    <string name="start_task_confirm">Start task</string>

    <string name="pr_wrong">Here is another example. Going from left to right, the circles get larger, and going from top to bottom they get darker.
        Therefore the answer has to be a circle which is the largest of the three sizes, and the darkest. Choices C and E are both the right size, but E is the only
       large circle with the correct shading. Thus E is the only drawing that fits in the pattern formed by the other circles. E is the answer that should be chosen.\n\n
        Please press \"Next\" to continue.
	</string>

    <string name="practiceq2">INSTRUCTIONS\n\nNow look at another example, which is quite different from either of the previous ones.\n\n
    Choose the figure that belongs at the \"?\" below, then press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="pr_explain">If you study the pattern you will see that going from left to right there is one more line in each figure
        than in the one to the left of it. Going from top to bottom, the number of lines in any figure is one less than in the figure just above it. Therefore, the
        missing figure should have three lines. The correct answer is choice C (the three lines, slanting in the proper direction).\n\n
        Please press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="ar_intro">INSTRUCTIONS\n\n
		&#8226; You will now be asked six more questions like the ones you just did. \n
		&#8226; For each question, decide what rules the pattern follows. Choose the answer that belongs in \"?\" by pressing the answer.\n
		&#8226; Many of the patterns are based on rules that are different from the ones in the sample items.\n
		If you are ready to begin, please press \"Next\".
	</string>
    <string name="start_now">Start Now</string>
    <string name="ar_instr_header">INSTRUCTIONS</string>
    <string name="ar_instr">Choose which figure belongs at the \"?\" by pressing the correct figure. Then press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <!-- Abstract reasoning -->

    <!-- 2D visualization -->
    <string name="sp_1_instr">INSTRUCTIONS\n\nLook at the figures below. The first figure is shaped like the letter L. The rest of the figures are like the first, except
        that they have been turned (rotated) in different directions. </string>
    <string name="sp_next">Please press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="sp_1_sol"> If you think of the figure at the left below as being made out of wire and lying on a table, the positions shown in each of the other four
        figures could be made simply by turning (rotating) the wire figure at the left around, without lifting it off the table. \n\n Please press \"Next\" to continue.</string>
    <string name="sp_2_instr">INSTRUCTIONS\n\nNow look at the next row of figures. The first figure is shaped like the letter P. But for  the rest of the drawings, even
        if they were turned (rotated), they would still be backwards; you would have to lift the figure at the left off the table and flip it over to make any of the
        other figures. </string>
    <string name="sp_intro"> INSTRUCTIONS\n\nIn this task each question has one figure at the left and five similar figures to the right of it. Only one of the five
        figures on the right exactly matches the figure at the left if you turn (rotate) it. The rest of the figures are backwards even when they are turned (rotated).</string>
    <string name="sp_3_instr">Now look at the sample question below.\nChoose the one figure which, when turned (rotated), exactly matches the figure at the left?</string>
    <string name="sp_3_sol">INSTRUCTIONS\n\nYou should have picked the fourth answer choice. All of the other choices have been \"lifted off the table and flipped over\"
        as well as turned (rotated), and thus are backwards. </string>
    <string name="sp_begin">For each question in this task, choose the one figure which, when turned (rotated), exactly matches the figure at the left.\n\n
        If you are ready to begin, please press \"Next\".</string>
    <string name="sp_question">Choose the one figure which, when turned (rotated), exactly matches the figure at the left.</string>
    <!-- 2D visualization -->

    <!-- Warning messages -->
    <string name="quit">Quit</string>
    <string name="resume">Resume</string>
    <string name="timeup">2 minutes up</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="msg2">You have not submitted a response yet.Your answers are important to us.\nPlease try to answer as best you can. If you are not willing to provide
        an answer, please press NEXT to continue.</string>
    <string name="msg3">You did not complete the question. Your answers are important to us. Please try to answer as best you can. If you are not willing to provide an
        answer, please press NEXT to continue.</string>
    <string name="quit_resume">Would you like to quit? Or go back to where you left off?</string>
    <!-- Warning messages -->

    <!--Context switch -->
    <string name="switch_ns">Switch to number section.</string>
    <string name="switch_ar">Switch to abstract reasoning.</string>
    <string name="switch_sv">Switch to spatial visualization.</string>
    <string name="sp_section_title">Spatial Visualization</string>
    <string name="reaction_time">Reaction Time</string>
    <!--Context switch -->

    <string name="userIdinstr">Please enter your user ID.\n\nThis is the same number you entered for the first part of the survey.</string>

    <!--Reaction time -->
    <string name="rt_complete">Thank you for completing the Reaction Time Test</string>
    <string name="rt_exit">You may now exit by tapping on the SPACEBAR</string>
    <string name="spacebar">SPACEBAR</string>
    <string name="end_thanks">Thank you for completing the test.</string>
    <string name="end_exit">You can now exit by tapping on the exit button below.</string>
    <string name="exit">Exit</string>
    <string name="exit_button_text">You may now exit by tapping on the exit button below.</string>
    <string name="reaction_instr1">This task measures your speed. You will be shown a black cross for a few seconds, followed by a red circle. Then the cross will
        appear again, followed by the circle, and so on.\n\n
        Your task is to:\n
        (1) hold your finger over the SPACEBAR button.\n
        (2) focus on the cross\n
        (3) each time you see the red circle press the SPACEBAR as quickly as you can\n\n
        When you are ready to begin, press the SPACEBAR button.</string>
    <!-- Reaction time -->

    <!-- Thurstone -->
    <string name="great_job">That is correct.</string>
    <string name="now_you_will_practice">Now you will practice.</string>
    <string name="seconds_rule">You will see each picture for 5 seconds. Make use of the time and study each picture carefully, for the full 5 seconds.</string>
    <string name="begin_instr">Press \'Next\' when you are ready to begin.</string>
    <string name="incorrect_ans">Incorrect, the picture you actually saw was this &#8230;</string>
    <string name="now_click">Now click on the picture you have seen.</string>
    <string name="pressnext">Please press \'Next\' to go to the next task.</string>
    <string name="thurs_instr">The next task measures your memory. You will see a series of pictures for 5 seconds each. You will then see the original picture along with
        several similar pictures. Your task is to pick which of the pictures is the one you saw previously.\n\n
        For example, you will see a picture like this &#8230;</string>
    <string name="instr_thurs_q">Tap the picture you studied, then press \'Next\'.</string>
    <string name="click_picture">Now click on the picture you have seen.</string>
    <string name="th_instr">Then later you will see the first picture along with several similar pictures, like these. Please tap the picture which is the same as the
        one you saw previously. </string>
    <string name="instr_thurs">Now, click on the picture you have studied.</string>
    <string name="thurs_example">Thurstone Example</string>
    <string name="thanks">Thank you for completing the test.</string>
    <string name="thurstone_title">Thurstone</string>
    <string name="real_test_instr">Now that you have practiced, it is time to begin the task.\n
        The procedure is the same as before. You will see each picture for 5 seconds.\n
        Use the time to study each picture carefully.\n\n
        When you are ready, press \'Begin\'.</string>
    <!-- Thurstone -->
</resources>
